[Music]
Asia is diverse there is no solution
that fits all especially when it comes
to retirement planning the population of
Asia is aging much faster than the rest
of the world
by 2050 the elderly population in Asia
will account for 63 percent of the
world's population aged 65 and above
in East and Southeast Asia alone the
senior population would be more than
double reaching 572.5 million
the rapid pace of this transition would
be a unique challenge to Asia more so
than any other Market
is your retirement saving sufficient to
generate monthly income after you retire
what is your top of Mind retirement
concern
[Music]
the cost of living in healthcare are
getting higher so our retirement savings
are tight foreign
legitimate concerns indeed people should
put more thoughts and efforts into their
retirement planning
in our recent market research we asked
families across Asia how much of a
retirement income is needed to maintain
a comfortable lifestyle in retirement we
found that people in Hong Kong Indonesia
and Malaysia need 73 to 100 of the
current monthly income to maintain a
comfortable lifestyle in retirement
however according to our retirement
income forecaster these people may get
around 33 of their current monthly
income at in time
there is clearly a huge gap between
people's expectations and reality
in the meantime inflation has driven up
cost of living
together with deglobalization
demographic reversals Rising interest
rates and macroeconomic volatility it
will become harder to generate
sustainable returns and yield the
traditional way
the pandemic has also raised concern
about securing retirement needs our
survey indicates that 63 percent of
respondents have become more concerned
about saving enough following the
pandemic as many as 43 have started to
save more
Market volatility will persist
investing early and staying invested
after retirement could help to withstand
long-term volatility and create
sustainable income for retirement
with more than 120 years of underground
investment experience in Asia we
understand everyone's retirement and
investment need is unique in Hong Kong
manual life is the largest mandatory
Provident fund provider we are also the
first in the market to introduce
retirement income solution to meet
people's needs before and after
retirement
we also recommend people to make
voluntary contributions and leverage tax
deductible all tax incentivized vehicles
to complement their compulsory pension
savings
finally you may also consider setting up
a separate Investment Portfolio that is
dedicated for retirement savings taking
into consideration risk return and
diversification needs
unsure of how much monthly income you
could have during retirement
is the retirement income forecaster to
find out your projected monthly income
after you retire
and through manulifi funds you can
identify the financial gap set
objectives and seek for the most
appropriate investment Solutions
talk to your investment advisor for
investment solutions that could meet
your retirement and investment needs
invest early and stay invested even
during retirement with Manulife
investment management
[Music]